<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[All Things (v8)]]></title>
  <link href="http://anthonyeden.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://anthonyeden.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-10T15:58:25-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://anthonyeden.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anthony Eden]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Testing REST APIs With Cucumber and Rack]]></title>
    <link href="http://anthonyeden.com/blog/2013/07/10/testing-rest-apis-with-cucumber-and-rack/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-10T15:48:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://anthonyeden.com/blog/2013/07/10/testing-rest-apis-with-cucumber-and-rack</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Author&#8217;s note: This is a repost of an post I originally wrote in 2011. I&#8217;m reposting it by request. Enjoy!</em></p>

<p>This evening Corey and I sat down and started looking into how we could make the tests live again. First we attempted to use Capybara directly, but ran into issues when trying to set HTTP headers. The DNSimple API uses Basic HTTP Authentication and thus we needed to set the header for that. We also need to set the Content-Type and Accept headers to ensure that Rails handles the input and output correctly. After peeling back some layers of the Capybara onion we landed upon Rack::Test. When using Rack, Capybara delegates request and response handling down to <a href="http://github.com/brynary/rack-test">Rack::Test</a>. At this point we decided to see if we could use Rack::Test directly in our step definitions, and it worked like a charm.</p>

<p>Rack::Test has a module called Rack::Test::Methods that can be mixed into a class to provide it with methods for get, post, put, delete as well as last_request, last_response, header and more. We mixed Rack::Test::Methods into the Cucumber world at the top of our API steps file like so:</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/aeden/660319.js"></script>


<p>Then our steps could simply call the Rack::Test methods directly. For example, here&#8217;s how to send the HTTP Basic Auth header:</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/aeden/660321.js"></script>


<p>And to set content type and accept headers:</p>

<script src="http://gist.github.com/aeden/660323.js"></script>


<p>And finally to actually send requests and test the responses. The entire api_steps.rb as it is right now looks like this:</p>

<script src="http://gist.github.com/aeden/660331.js"></script>


<p>And here is an example of a Cucumber feature that uses the API steps:</p>

<script src="http://gist.github.com/aeden/660337.js"></script>


<p>I doubt we&#8217;ve ended up with the ultimate final set of steps that can be used repeatedly for testing RESTful APIs, however I think it is an excellent start. I&#8217;m still on the fence about how to check the response body, specifically whether it is better to match the response body as a string or to actually parse it and write custom steps for each of the different types of objects, but time will tell.</p>

<p>As usual pairing with Corey resulted in some good code, a usable solution and something that I think others will benefit from as well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Internet, Nomadic Employment and Opportunity]]></title>
    <link href="http://anthonyeden.com/blog/2013/05/31/the-internet-nomadic-employment-and-opportunity/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-31T18:41:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://anthonyeden.com/blog/2013/05/31/the-internet-nomadic-employment-and-opportunity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Note: I originally planned for my next post to be about my time spent working on Java and my deep immersion into Open Source development. I might get to it at some point, but this is not that post.</p>

<p>When @dje showed me the World Wide Web for the first time he said that this was the future. At the time I had no idea how right he was, nor did I (nor anyone else for that matter) really understand how significant the impact would be, on all facets of our lives.</p>

<p>In 1998 I came back to the US after having lived in Vienna for a little less than a year. I finished up my studies at the University of Miami and married my wife. Initially we had a civil wedding in the tiny Town of Malabar, a rural town on the East Coast of Florida where I grew up. We were actually the first, and perhaps the only, couple to be married in the town hall. My wife and I both agreed that after school was done we would go back to France and have a traditional French wedding with her family. We also decided that we would stay in France for a while and see where our life together would take us. Moving to three different countries in three years pretty much set in stone what would be the story of our life so far.</p>

<p>How does this all tie back to the Internet? Well simply put none of it would have been quite the same without the ability to relocate across the world and yet still be able to communicate so effectively with friends, family and
employers. The former were easier to handle than the later, but eventually the Internet has made communication with <em>everyone</em> simpler and more practical.</p>

<p>Which brings me to today: communicating through the Internet has become the primary mode of communication for people like me, people who can&#8217;t settle in one place for any extended period of time. We&#8217;re modern-day nomads who desperately want to be able to interact with the world, to maintain our virtual connections as we explore the world around us. Unfortunately there are still some significant hold-outs that haven&#8217;t quite caught up with the way of life I&#8217;ve chosen. Most of these holdouts are in some way regulated by national and local governments, which probably has a lot to do with their inability to catch up. Let&#8217;s look at some examples.</p>

<h2>Telecom and Internet</h2>

<p>I chose telecom and Internet providers first because they are the lifeline to my primary means of communication. Without Internet everything I do breaks down. I cannot communicate with my family abroad, I cannot run my business, I cannot do much of anything. So where are we today with telecom and Internet providers for nomads? First off there are some countries where the monopolies of old-school telecom providers have been broken and where you can actually get a SIM card for an iPhone, plug it in and use tethering without having to a.) have a 2 year subscription and b.) pay fees just because you&#8217;re actually <em>using</em> the data pipe that these providers claim to be providing. I feel like that might come off as overly bitter, but that&#8217;s because in far too many countries this is still not the case. Even in France, where we have Free mobile, which has caused an upheaval for French mobile providers due to their extreme price cut (17 EUR for unlimited voice, SMS and data for the iPhone, including teathering), you still have to actually have a physical address to qualify. So there&#8217;s still no good option for nomads sadly. 3, in the UK, does a pretty good job of making it easy to walk in to a store and buy a SIM that works, but they seem to be the exception, not the rule. Ultimately mobile data providers will likely be forced to become the data provider for the wanderer, so I hope they figure out pretty soon how make it easier for us nomads to wander.</p>

<p>Back in the early 2000&#8217;s I worked with @dje a bit on mesh networking with wifi. Sadly it never went anywhere. Again, using Free as an example, you can try to bounce from Freebox to Freebox and temporarily borrow some of the bandwidth from the Freebox owner if you are a Free customer, however the bandwidth seems to be severely limited and often the connection simply does not work. Nice idea, but it&#8217;s mostly a flop for the moment. This type of infrastructure probably has to be treated like roads and basic education - developed and funded by the general public with an eye towards use by all, resident or not, in order for it to actually work. That is, after all, what public government is good for, handling infrastructure needs that are too big for private enities to develop.</p>

<p>So, telecom and Internet for the nomad is largely a struggle in finding a patchwork of access points, including friends&#8217; networks, McDonalds and Starbucks and the occasional tethering SIM if we&#8217;re lucky.</p>

<h2>Medical Insurance and Health Care</h2>

<p>If you&#8217;ve ever travelled outside of your homeland and needed to go to a hospital due to an unforseen circumstance (I say as I look at my right knee, which I severely tweaked while snowboarding back in 1997) you know that you&#8217;ll probably have to pull out your credit card as proof of payment. Health insurance doesn&#8217;t typically travel well. Of course you can buy health care that will reimburse you for hospital and doctor stays abroad, but you&#8217;ll likely pay even more on top of the already high prices for your &#8220;benefits&#8221;. When you actually have to claim, don&#8217;t expect an easy ride either.</p>

<p>Right now the only solution seems to be to get the initial emergency treatment in the foreign country and then make your way back to wherever you claim residency as quickly as possible to minimize your out-of-pocket expenses. Either that or have deep pockets so you can just pay for treatment locally or relocate to where you can get really good treatment at significantly lower costs. Thailand seems to be a good destination for the new-world-order of low-cost, decent quality health care (at least according to second-hand stories and reports I&#8217;ve read).</p>

<h2>Banking</h2>

<p>I&#8217;m not talking about the ability to bank remotely once you&#8217;ve established an account, banks have gotten so much better with this in recent years. I&#8217;m talking about the act of banking</p>

<h2>Government Services (Read: Taxation)</h2>

<p>Originally I called out inadaquacy of payroll companies, but the truth is that payroll companies are facilitators to proper reporting for taxation, and that&#8217;s their primary function. The real problem is that government taxation is stuck on yearly cycles and tied directly to residency.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Projects Moved: erl-dns and dnstest]]></title>
    <link href="http://anthonyeden.com/blog/2013/05/06/projects-moved-erl-dns-and-dnstest/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-06T21:52:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://anthonyeden.com/blog/2013/05/06/projects-moved-erl-dns-and-dnstest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two projects which I&#8217;ve been spending considerable time on lately, erl-dns and dnstest, have now been moved under the aetrion organization on Github.</p>

<h2>erl-dns</h2>

<p>The <a href="https://github.com/aetrion/erl-dns">erl-dns project</a> is an authoritative DNS server written in Erlang. Warning: don&#8217;t try this at home.</p>

<h2>dnstest</h2>

<p>The <a href="https://github.com/aetrion/dnstest">dnstest</a> project is a collection of regression tests from the PowerDNS 3 regression test suite which I&#8217;ve switched over to run in an Erlang test harness. I use these tests to test the correctness of the responses from erl-dns.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll be writing more about both of these projects in the future, especially as we move erl-dns into production at <a href="https://dnsimple.com">DNSimple</a>.</p>

<p>Update your forks if necessary. Thanks!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hacking CGI and Perl]]></title>
    <link href="http://anthonyeden.com/blog/2013/05/04/hacking-cgi-and-perl/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-04T20:37:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://anthonyeden.com/blog/2013/05/04/hacking-cgi-and-perl</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a few months of slinging some pretty incredible HTML (not really) I was stymied by one particular type of tag: I couldn&#8217;t do anything with this FORM tag. Well, I could render a form on the page, but that&#8217;s not very useful by itself. When in doubt I turned to the most obvious guide: <a href="http://dje.io">@dje</a>. I asked Darrin what I could do to get the stuff from forms and do something with it and his answer was: look into CGI.</p>

<p>At this point I had no idea of how my HTML pages were even showing up when I was using a browser. All I knew was that I had to put the files in a particular directory and that if I had a file called index.html in a directory then that HTML content would show up when the URL in the browser was for the enclosing directory. After a bit of research I came to the conclusion that CGI was something you did with Perl (yes, this was not the correct conclusion, but it lead me to the next step.</p>

<p>Somehow I found a book about Perl. The actual title was Teach Yourself Perl in 21 Days, published in 1994. I think I finished it in less than 21 days - learning a programming language for the first time was amazing. I felt like I had found something powerful and that now I could make a computer do anything. I figured out how to put scripts up on the server where they could be executed (again with quite a bit of help from Darrin, I&#8217;m sure) and I was off to the races.</p>

<p>Over the next two years I wrote a lot of perl scripts. I wrote perl scripts to take form input and send it via email. Then I wrote perl scripts to take form input and store it in a MySQL database. My scripts became more and more complicated. I began writing scripts that used Perl 5&#8217;s object syntax. I even wrote a content publishing system for the University of Miami&#8217;s newspaper.</p>

<p>In 1996 I spent a year abroad in Vienna, focusing on music. When I returned in 1997 I realized that there were some things I&#8217;d probably never be able to do with Perl (most likely this isn&#8217;t true, but this is what I thought).</p>

<p>I really wanted to be able to develop software for my Mac (which I believe was running OS 9 at this point). I looked at the tomes that Apple execpted OS 9 developers to understand and came to the conclusion that I was neither ready for that, nor was I ready for the C programming language which was the language of choice for developing OS 9 applications. Again, I believe it was @dje who came to the rescue, pointing me to a new language which was recently released called Java.</p>

<p>Next up: Java and Open Source</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beginning]]></title>
    <link href="http://anthonyeden.com/blog/2013/05/01/beginning/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-01T11:24:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://anthonyeden.com/blog/2013/05/01/beginning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When you don&#8217;t know where to start, you start from the beginning. In this case though everything before 1994 would probably be mostly useless, even if it would occasionally be amusing. Thus, let&#8217;s start in 1994.</p>

<p>In 1994 I entered the University of Miami as a freshmen with my major as Music Composition. I can&#8217;t recall why I chose to go to college - I suppose that&#8217;s what a kid from a middle-class family is supposed to do, so I did it. I was very fortunate in that my father worked for the University of Miami for many years and essentially provided a means for me to go to U of M for free. No doubt that&#8217;s another reason I went: it was essentially an extension of my parents taking care of me. 4 more years of fun and frolicking, right?</p>

<p>Anyhow, back to the story. As a freshman I lived in the dorms, had a meal plan, and essentially didn&#8217;t need much money, but a little wouldn&#8217;t hurt. My brother (<a href="http://dje.io">@dje</a>) was already a Sophomore and was working in the computer labs. The labs always needed lab techs to sit at the front desk and give students access to machines, so he hooked me up with a job doing just that. Other duties included running back to the printer room to grab printouts for the grad students who used the line printers, rebooting machines that failed (this was back in the Mac OS 8 days) and trying to keep from being bored. About the best part was shutting down the labs at the end of the day and then having LAN parties playing Marathon.</p>

<p>One day Darrin comes to me and says he wants to show me something on his computer. He pulls up this application and tells me that this is the future. The application was Mosaic and Darrin was showing me the world wide web. Mosaic had been released in 1993, so this was really <a href="http://info.cern.ch/">the early days</a> in the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Wide_Web">history of the web</a>. None the less, I was interested in understanding how I could make something with it right from the beginning. I decided that I would make a web site where I could put up my music along with photos of artwork from a friend and written works by another friend. I can&#8217;t remember what the name of the site was, but I do recall it was pretty awful. The thing is: it didn&#8217;t matter that it was awful, all that mattered was that I could build it using nothing more than View Source and a few tutorials. About the only programming experience I had at this point was some Basic.</p>

<p>In short: the web was an amazing, open environment that has been central in my life for almost 20 years now and I am truly thankful for all of the people who have contributed to make it what it is over that time.</p>

<p>Next up: Hacking my Way Through CGI and Perl</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[One-hundred Percent DNSimple]]></title>
    <link href="http://anthonyeden.com/blog/2013/04/04/one-hundred-percent-dnsimple/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-04T06:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://anthonyeden.com/blog/2013/04/04/one-hundred-percent-dnsimple</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tomorrow is my last day at LivingSocial. After 2 years of being an employee I am now switching all of my focus to my own business. I am excited and nervous about this step, but I feel it is time.</p>

<p>Working at LivingSocial has been an incredible experience. It was often quite challenging due to the sheer volume of traffic that LivingSocial handles on a daily basis. I had the pleasure of working on a wide range of projects, from payment systems to email delivery systems. I worked on the initial version of the 918F registration site and watched that project take off. I also worked with the Takeout &amp; Delivery team to help improve restaurant ordering systems. It has been a helluva a ride, however now it is time to get focused on DNSimple.</p>

<p>The first DNSimple commit occurred on April 6th, 2010. That is almost 3 years to the day. From a little side project it has grown significantly and steadily. We now have over 6400 customers who rely on us. We have more than 19,000 domains registered through us and if this year continues on track then we should exceed $1 million in revenue for the year 2013. I imagine a world where buying a domain name, managing DNS and purchasing SSL certificates are all experiences that are enjoyable, easy and painless. There is a lot of room for improvement, both in our offerings and in the industry as a whole, and I am thrilled to be working towards that goal full time now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[All Things v8]]></title>
    <link href="http://anthonyeden.com/blog/2012/09/27/all-things-v8/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T12:13:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://anthonyeden.com/blog/2012/09/27/all-things-v8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My old Wordpress blog got hacked (yay PHP!) so now I&#8217;m moving All Things over to Github Pages. Here we are. I might move old content over, I might not, we will see.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
