<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[All Things (v8)]]></title>
  <link href="http://anthonyeden.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://anthonyeden.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-04T16:10:20-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://anthonyeden.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anthony Eden]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[One-hundred Percent DNSimple]]></title>
    <link href="http://anthonyeden.com/blog/2013/04/04/one-hundred-percent-dnsimple/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-04T06:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://anthonyeden.com/blog/2013/04/04/one-hundred-percent-dnsimple</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tomorrow is my last day at LivingSocial. After 2 years of being an employee I am now switching all of my focus to my own business. I am excited and nervous about this step, but I feel it is time.</p>

<p>Working at LivingSocial has been an incredible experience. It was often quite challenging due to the sheer volume of traffic that LivingSocial handles on a daily basis. I had the pleasure of working on a wide range of projects, from payment systems to email delivery systems. I worked on the initial version of the 918F registration site and watched that project take off. I also worked with the Takeout &amp; Delivery team to help improve restaurant ordering systems. It has been a helluva a ride, however now it is time to get focused on DNSimple.</p>

<p>The first DNSimple commit occurred on April 6th, 2010. That is almost 3 years to the day. From a little side project it has grown significantly and steadily. We now have over 6400 customers who rely on us. We have more than 19,000 domains registered through us and if this year continues on track then we should exceed $1 million in revenue for the year 2013. I imagine a world where buying a domain name, managing DNS and purchasing SSL certificates are all experiences that are enjoyable, easy and painless. There is a lot of room for improvement, both in our offerings and in the industry as a whole, and I am thrilled to be working towards that goal full time now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[All Things v8]]></title>
    <link href="http://anthonyeden.com/blog/2012/09/27/all-things-v8/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T12:13:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://anthonyeden.com/blog/2012/09/27/all-things-v8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My old Wordpress blog got hacked (yay PHP!) so now I&#8217;m moving All Things over to Github Pages. Here we are. I might move old content over, I might not, we will see.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
